Finding Aid for Douglas MacArthur collection
William L. Clements Library, University of Michigan
- Papers pertaining to the 42nd (Rainbow) Division
  - Kenneth A. Sutherland Notebook. (Box 6)
    35 letters, documents, publications, and ephemera related to reunions of the 42nd Division, 1918-1937. Includes two letters by Douglas MacArthur, 1931-1932.
- Photographs and miscellaneous papers pertaining to Douglas MacArthur (Box 7)
  - Aerial photographs and negatives, 91st Reconnaissance Squadron, 1918 October 10.
    40 aerial photographs and negatives, taken by the 91st Recon. Squadron, [France].
  - Miscellaneous photographs and papers. (Box 8)
    11 miscellaneous photographs and additional papers related to Douglas MacArthur.
    - [Undated, WWI era]. Photograph: full length posed photo of Douglas MacArthur holding a swagger stick. Signed "To a beloved comrade-in-arms of the Rainbow"
    - [1917-1919]. Photograph Identification card of Brig. Gen. Douglas MacArthur, Chief of Staff 42nd Division., 1 item
    - 1932 March 14. Photograph: full length portrait of Douglas MacArthur in uniform. Signed "With cordial regard."
    - [1944 October 20]. Photograph: General Douglas MacArthur walking ashore at the Leyte Landing, Signed.
    - [1945 January 9]. Photograph: International News (wire service) photo; Luzon, Philippines. Depicting the General walking ashore.
    - 1945 February 25. Photograph: International News (wire service) photo; Luzon, Philippines. Depicting the General standing with aides on the Bataan peninsula.
    - 1945 August 14. The Abiline Reporter, vol. 65, no. 58; Abiline, Texas.. Front page article "Peace! Key Men in Drive to Victory Over Japan" includes pictures of Chester Nimitz and Douglas MacArthur., located in Oversize manuscripts
    - 1949. Photograph: Portrait of the General, inscribed and signed "To Francis With life-long friendship. Douglas MacArthur Tokyo 1949."
      located in "Miscellaneous letters and documents pertaining to Douglas MacArthur" series, with Douglas MacArthur ALS to Frances [S. Rockwell]; 1898 February 5
    - 1951 April 19. Photograph: General Douglas MacArthur Addresses Members of Congress, U.S. Army Photograph SC361740-S.. Signed by Douglas MacArthur and Vice President Alben W. Barkley.
    - 1951 December 3. Printed advertisement/RSVP: Poor Richard's 47th Annual Banquet..
    - 1964 April 6. New York Times, vol. CXIII, no. 39,789., Regarding the death of Douglas MacArthur.; located in Oversize manuscripts
    - 1971 January 26. Printed Douglas MacArthur envelope and postal cancellation, first day of issue. Post. Signed by Jean MacArthur.
    - Undated. Document (copy). List of Units making up the Rainbow Division. Submitted by a member of Battalion E, 149th U.S.F.A.
- Published works
  - James, D[orris] Clayton. The Years of MacArthur. Boston: Houghton Mifflin, v. 1, 1970 v. 2, 1975 v. 3, 1985. (Volume 1)
  - Lowitt, Richard, and Harry S. Truman. The Truman-MacArthur Controversy. Chicago: Rand McNally, 1967. (Volume 2)
  - MacArthur, Douglas. Duty, Honor, Country: a Pictorial Autobiography. New York: McGraw-Hill, 1965. (Volume 3)
  - MacArthur, Douglas. Military Demolitions. [Fort Leavenworth, Kan., Staff college press], 1909. Signed on cover by Douglas MacArthur and presented in a custom blue clamshell box. (Volume 4)
  - MacArthur, Douglas.Reminiscences. New York, McGraw-Hill, 1964. (Volume 5)
  - MacArthur, Douglas, and Norman Vincent Peale. Revitalizing a Nation: a Statement of Beliefs, Opinions, And Policies Embodied In the Public Pronouncements of Douglas MacArthur. Chicago: Heritage Foundation; distributed by Garden City Books, Garden City, N.Y, 1952. Signed on title page by Douglas MacArthur. Enclosed: Printed program for "Reception and Luncheon for General of the Army Douglas MacArthur," Michigan State College, Kellogg Center, East Lansing, Michigan, May 15, 1952. Enclosed: Manuscript notes on MacArthur's speech, taken by Duane N. Diedrich, at the Kellogg Center. Enclosed: typed explanatory note by the regarding the volume and enclosures, dated August 21, 2010. (Volume 6)
  - MacArthur, Douglas, and Vorin E. Whan. A Soldier Speaks: Public Papers and Speeches of General of the Army, Douglas MacArthur. New York: Praeger, 1965. (Volume 7)
  - Pearlman, Michael D. Truman & MacArthur: Policy, Politics, and the Hunger for Honor and Renown. Bloomington: Indiana University Press, 2008. (Volume 8)
  - Rasor, Eugene L. General Douglas MacArthur, 1880-1964: Historiography and Annotated Bibliography. Westport, Conn.: Greenwood Press, 1994. (Volume 9)
  - Representative Speeches of General of the Army Douglas MacArthur. Washington: U.S.G.P.O., 1964. (Volume 10)
  - Spanier, John W. The Truman-MacArthur Controversy and the Korean War. Cambridge, Mass.: Belknap Press, 1959. (Volume 11)
  - Whitney, Courtney. Macarthur: His Rendezvous with History. New York, Knopf, 1956. (Volume 12)
  - Composite volume containing copies of: (Volume 13)
    - 1. MacArthur, Douglas, and Norman Vincent Peale. Revitalizing a Nation: a Statement of Beliefs, Opinions, and Policies Embodied in the Public Pronouncements of Douglas MacArthur. Chicago: Heritage Foundation; distributed by Garden City Books, Garden City, N.Y, 1952.
    - 2. Military Situation in the Far East. Washington: U.S.G.P.O., 1951 part I (pages 1-724).
    - 3. Address of the General of the Army Douglas MacArthur at a Joint Meeting of the Two Houses in the Hall of the House of Representatives, April 19, 1951. Washington: U.S.G.P.O., 1951.
    - 4. Individual Views of Certain Members of the Joint Committee on Armed Services and Foreign Relations of the United States Senate Relating to the Hearings Held on the Dismissal of General MacArthur and the Military Situation in the Far East May 3-June 27, 1951. Washington: U.S.G.P.O., 1951.
The MacArthur papers, MacArthur Memorial Library and Archives. Norfolk, Virginia.
Bleecker Houston papers, William L. Clements Library, The University of Michigan, Ann Arbor.
Erwin Nieswand papers, William L. Clements Library, The University of Michigan, Ann Arbor.
Cheseldine, Raymond M. Ohio in the Rainbow; Official Story of the 166th Infantry, 42nd Division, in the World War. Columbus, Ohio: F.J. Heer, 1924.
Cooke, James J. The Rainbow Division in the Great War, 1917-1919. Westport, Conn.: Praeger, 1994.
Reilly, Henry Joseph. Americans All: The Rainbow at War; Official History of the 42nd Rainbow Division in the World War. Columbus, Ohio: F.J. Heer, 1936.
Schaller, Michael. MacArthur, Douglas. American National Biography Online, Feb. 2000.
Whitney, Courtney. MacArthur: His Rendezvous with History. New York, Knopf, 1956.